Contact

georgeshagov@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/georgeshagov (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Unix

C++

Oracle

Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual)

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Problem Solving (Basic)

ITIL® Intermediate Certificate in IT Operational Support and Analysis

PRINCE2® Foundation Certificate

ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

Python (Basic)

Publications

"C++ Forever"

"Matrix linking"

"Inventing mutex"

Shooting Fibonacci Rabbits

"Sharp as C"

Patents

Method of composing (linking) of software applications

Synchronization object

George Shagov

C++ IT Engineer

Moscow

Summary

PROFILE

- Over 20 years of experience in IT, C++
- Over 15 years in Finance Trading IT Services. C++, Linux, HFT
- Over 6 years in IBIT Management

Major Skills: C++98,11,14,17,20/Linux/Perl/Bash/VIM/git

Secondary: Perl/MySQL/Python/Java/JS/PostgreSQL/block-chain/

Ethereum/Bitcoin/Cryptography/Security/Kafka

Personal Achievement: IQ:Mensa,2Patents,Articles

Experience

GeorgeShagov

Self Development

October 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Moscow, Moscow City, Russia

Major Skills: C++14,17,20/Linux/Perl/Bash/VIM/git

Secondary: Perl/MySQL/Python/Java/JS/PostgreSQL/block-chain/Ethereum/

Bitcoin/Cryptography/Security

Personal Achievement: IQ:Mensa

LATOKEN

C++ Trading Core Services Leader

June 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Moscow, Russia

Main responsibilities

- Trading Core Service Architectural Design
- High Volume Matching Engine (ME), C++ Component, Kafka
- High Volume Balance Engine (BE), C++ Component, Kafka
- Low Latency HFT Gateway, implemented in WebSockets, C++ Component, Kafka
- Low Latency Market Data Adapter, WebSockets, C++ Component, Kafka
- Master PostgreSQL DataBase modelling, implementation and support
- Transferring data from mySQL to PostgreSQL DB
- Access Management to Trading Production Environment

Page 1 of 4

- Security Management, Two-Factor Authentication, SSH Key Management, Certificate Management

UBS Investment Bank 9 years 6 months

IB IT Solution Owner

February 2012 - May 2018 (6 years 4 months)

Moscow, Russian Federation

INTRO: The main goal of UBS Moscow office is to provide security trading brokerage service at Moscow stock exchange (MOEX) for the clients, located both locally and Ldn (worldwide).

FUNCTION: Service Owner

RESPONSIBILITIES: In continuously business changing conditions my duty is to conduct the full project life-cycle, which includes: • client facing; • planning;

risk analysis;
 documentation;
 development;
 change management;
 deployment;
 testing;
 support;
 compliance;

SKILLS: Unix/Linux, Windows, C++, Java, Oracle. MSSQL, variety of the technologies, VIM.

Technical Lead

December 2008 - January 2012 (3 years 2 months)

Moscow, Russian Federation

FUNCTION: Technical Lead

RESPONSIBILITIES: Development, Deployment and Support of Marked Feeds. This is the variety of different infrastructures, environments and services united in the purpose of providing connectivity between MOEX and internal UBS systems.

SKILLS: Unix/Linux, Windows, C++, Java, Oracle. MSSQL, data processing (PowerCenter), variety of the technologies, VIM.

Deutsche Bank
IBIT Software engineer
October 2003 - July 2007 (3 years 10 months)

INTRO

In the beginning of 2000th there had been created at Moscow "Pushkin Project". The main target for this establishment was the creation of Order Management System with the purpose to conduct the IB trading at the different stock exchanges world wide, like (NYSE), LSE, NASDAQ, etc. "Arina" solution served as a cross platform system for equity market program/algorithmic

trading and direct market access. "Arina" was the winner of the European Banking Technology Awards 2004 as Best Use of IT in Wholesale Banking. RESPONSIBILITIES

The core of "Arina" solution there had been so-called Basket Manager Service, which had been written in C++ and run under Solaris SPARC platform. I was involved as the member of the team who was responsible for Service Life Cycle. My personal responsibility was Cash SOM Service Process. As a process owner I conducted MCCS (market cross) and Order Modification Automation projects. The feature of the second one for instance allows trader to automatically apply the changes (amendments) received from the external system (XOM) to all submissions (sub-orders) which were cut/made from the original order.

SKILLS:

Unix/Solaris, Windows, C++, Oracle, variety of the technologies, VIM.

Epicor Software Software engineer February 2002 - June 2003 (1 year 5 months)

INTRO:

Scala Business Solutions N.V. (now it is Epicor; epicor.com) considered to be one of the biggest ERP solution being offered at the marked today. (As a sample it might be said that Scala was chosen (by Microsoft) like company of the year in ERP solutions).

RESPONSIBILITIES

I was involved like C++ (middleware) developer in process of preparing, bug fixing, tuning, optimizing of new product of Scala, which had a name iScala 2.2.

SKILLS:

Windows, C++, MSSQL, variety of the technologies

Emplifi Inc

Software engineer

July 2000 - November 2001 (1 year 5 months)

US, PA

INTRO:

Emplifi Inc provided consulting business in the US. I had participated in three software projects for the following US companies as a contractor:

- Corning; www.corning.com
- US. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) (www.hud.gov)
- SendantMobility; www.cendantmobility.com

RESPONSIBILITIES

C++ (middleware) developer

SKILLS:

Windows, C++, MSSQL, variety of the technologies

Education

Bauman Moscow State Technical University

Master's Degree, Radio, Television, and Digital Communication · (1990 - 1996)